Frederick O'Hara

Software Developer Intern at Trident Contract Management

ohar0046@gmail.com

Summary

Grounded in agile project management and product ownership, I am excited to be expanding my knowledge and skills in programming as a Software Developer Intern. As I work to complete my Associate's degree in software development, my dream is to become a part of a great team developing smart code that benefits from a deep understanding of many different perspectives. I also seek to find, implement, and coach better ways to develop software.

Skills & Expertise

Apex Programming

HTML

CSS

JavaScript

Scrum

Git

Java

PHP

Project Coordination

Content Management Systems

Microsoft Excel

Microsoft Office

Customer Service

Proposal Writing

Usability Testing

Administrative Office Support

CRM

CMS

Microsoft Access

Strategic Planning

jQuery

Bootstrap

Certifications

Certified Scrum Master

Scrum Alliance License 000450565 September 2015 to September 2017

Shaping up with Angular.js

Code School

Experience

Software Developer Intern at Trident Contract Management

March 2016 - Present (5 months)

Develop software for database, back-end, and front-end systems. Projects involve utilizing the Java programming language to perform Salesforce integrations and other customized data and contract management services.

Coach Scrum agile development practices.

Web Project Coordinator at Johnson Health Tech NA

March 2014 - March 2016 (2 years 1 month)

Product Owner

- Managed and contributed to website projects as part of an agile web team within a waterfall organization
- Developed and maintained project vision through road mapping
- Worked with cross-functional teams to prototype project requirements and goals
- Managed and refined project feature increment backlog
- Worked with stakeholders to identify, scope, and schedule feature development

Scrum Master

- Promoted continuous improvement of the development process as a Certified Scrum Master
- Removed impediments to successful development through cross-functional collaboration
- Facilitated Scrum team meetings to maximize meeting productivity and efficacy

Project Coordinator

- Inspected product increments for quality and adherence to specification
- Contributed to site design and user experience through collaboration with creative professionals

Content Manager

- Edited content and page layouts on more than 40 global sites in multiple languages using custom content management systems as well as editing from within development environments
- Managed product database change requests and train users on database interface and best practices
- Worked across departments to integrate data changes that must work across independent software platforms

Ticketing System Manager

- Managed ticketing system workflow from requirement verification and acceptance to execution and approval
- Acted as stakeholder of custom software system and initiate and manage software improvement projects

Project Assistant at Sundial Software

August 2011 - March 2014 (2 years 8 months)

Website testing, proposal drafting, data mining, and special assignments as needed. I also performed basic administrative support such as printer and software support.

Project work included collaborating with the President, Sales, and Recruiting on a CRM customization project for Sundial.

Weekend Night Manager at Princeton Club - East Madison

February 2010 - August 2011 (1 year 7 months)

Overnight security and reception as only employee in building open 24 hrs.

Student Office Support at University of Minnesota

September 2006 - December 2007 (1 year 4 months)

Reception, job search database management, and general office duties.

Summer Assistant Administrator, Summer Assistant, Interim Administrator at University of Minnesota

May 2005 - August 2007 (2 years 4 months)

Variety of information desk, conference check-in/out, and administrative roles. Tasks performed included: reception, billing/receiving, contract editing and administration.

Education

Madison Area Technical College

Programmer/Analyst, Web Progammer, 2015 - 2017

Grade: 3.885

Activities and Societies: Madison Information Technology Association member

University of Minnesota-Twin Cities

Bachelor's degree, Communication, General, Minor in Russian Language, 2004 - 2007

Grade: 3.2

Activities and Societies: Study abroad semester (St. Petersburg, Russia), Fencing Club, Student Government.

Saint Mary's University of Minnesota

Post Secondary Enrollment Options Program, 2003 - 2004

Grade: 3.7

Activities and Societies: Choir, Band, Jazz Band

Courses

Programmer/Analyst, Web Progammer

Madison Area Technical College

PHP Web with MySQL 10152166
Intro Prog with JavaScript 10152119
Website Development-XHTML 10152120

Intro to Database	10152124
Java Programming	10152111
SQL Database Programming	10152125
Object-Oriented Design w/UML	10152130

Volunteer Experience

Teacher's Assistant - ESL at St. Petersburg State University

August 2005 - December 2005

Conversation, culture, and idiomatic expression teaching

Honors and Awards

Make A Diference Award, Outstanding Team Member Award

Conference & Event Services Department

August 2006

First employee to receive both awards simultaneously.

Languages

English (Native or bilingual proficiency)

Russian (Elementary proficiency)

Test Scores

Typing Test

January 2014 Score:58 WPM Adjusted

Proveit! typing test

Interests

Books, new software, hiking, running.

Frederick O'Hara

Software Developer Intern at Trident Contract Management

ohar0046@gmail.com



Contact Frederick on LinkedIn